

SHEFALI GOEL

Automation Test Engineer

A Senior Quality Engineer having 6.5 years of experience in automation and manual testing using latest tools and technologies available in the market. I believe in achieving good test coverage using automation and set up a continuous integration & continuous delivery model.

Get in touch!

Mobile:

+91-8178090283

Email:

shefali.goel8@gmail.com

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/shefali-goel-9ab74972/

Skills

JAVA Selenium Cucumber

BDD Maven TestNG Junit

Web Services API Testing

SOAP REST SOAP UI

Jenkins GIT JIRA

Splunk HP ALM Banking Domain

Retail Commercial Devops

Financial Services SQL SAP GUI

Postman Selenium Webdriver

Agile Methodology Functional Testing

Regression testing Sanity Testing

Projects

Commonwealth Bank of Australia- DOT (Dec 2020-Ongoing) Lloyds Banking Group (June 2017 - Dec 2020) Walmart (Dec 2015 - June 2017)

Work Experience

Commonwealth Bank of Australia

Test Analyst | Dec 2020 - Present | Bangalore

- End to End validations with multiple applications in banking domain.
- Involved in Selenium Automation testing using java with BDD Framework.
- Involved in Manual testing, Master Test Plan. Test Planning, Requirement analysis, Test case creation, Defect tracking/logging, and Test execution and End of Test report.
- Have validated Credit Cards, Personal loan and Personal overdraft applications in Branch and all online applications according to client requirements and raised defects in JIRA according to Defect lifecycle.
- Managing team of 2 members as Test Lead
- Tools: Postman, Sql developer, Eclipse, Soap UI
- Skills: Selenium Webdriver, Java, TestNG, Postman, JIRA, Functional Testing, Regression Testing, MySQL, GIT and Agile Methodology.

Wipro Technologies

Senior Project Engineer | Aug 2015 - Dec 2020 | Bangalore

- Involved in End to End Testing features including functional, automation testing.
- Tested multiple parallel releases including Android, Web, IOS, and Tablet applications.
- Developed Automation framework from scratch using Java selenium includes Cucumber and POM with page factories and used across 10 different teams.
- Enhanced debugging of automation framework using log4j, implemented
 extent reports for visualization of execution output, implemented listeners for capturing screenshots.
- Involved in Manual testing, Master Test Plan. Test Planning, Requirement analysis, Test case creation, Defect tracking/logging, and Test execution and End of Test report
- Proficient in different types of testing namely Functional Testing, Accessibility testing, Smoke Testing, Sanity Testing, Regression and End to End testing.
- Tools Selenium, Java, Cucumber, Maven, TestNG, Junit, ALM, Jira, Splunk, MySQL, Jenkins, Git, Devops, LISA, Mainframe(Basic)

Awards & Achievements

- Microsoft Azure Al Fundamental Certified in month of Feb 2022.
- Microsoft Azure Fundamental Certified in month of oct 2021
- Awarded by client as a "Star of the month for excellent performance as an automation in month of Aug 2019.
- Have SDET and DEVOPS Training Certified in WIPRO.
- Recognition as a good tester for project and got multiple times winner circle points in Wipro

Education

PES University:

Master of Technology - CGPA 8.9

GGSIP University:

Bachelor of Science - CPI 81.22